In the not too distant future, somewhere in time and space, Mike Nelson and his robot pals are caught in an endless chase.
Pursued by a woman whose name is Pearl, an evil gal who wants to rule the world.
She threw a few things in her purse, and in her rocket ship she hunts him all across the universe.
I'll get ya! I'll send him cheesy movies. In the worst, I can't find.
He'll have to sit and watch them all in a monitor his mind.
Now keep in mind Mike can't control whether movies begin or end.
He'll try to keep his sanity with the help of his robot friends.
Robot rule, don't care about your eyes, juicy, don't serve a cat meow.
I am Primp.
You wonder how he eats and breathes, and other science facts.
Just repeat to yourself it's just a show.
I should really just relax.
Oh Mystery Science Theater 3000.
[Siren]
Mike, bro, gypsy, front and center people.
Hello and welcome. Today is business casual day here in the Satellite of Love.
You see, relieving people from the strict conventions of business attire creates a more informal environment.
Get in here, which contributes to productivity and a general sense of well-being for all employees.
El Servo, you know we're not a business so why do we need a business casual day?
Yes we do. To help us all I've codified the parameters of business casual day. There's your copy.
Well I just don't think we need a business casual day.
Yes, yes we do Mike.
Why?
Because of productivity and morale and stuff. Well let's review.
No chaps without pants. Mike. Number two, no sheer camisoles. Mike.
Number three, no tola shoes or sandals or spiked heels. Mike.
Okay well, it seems pretty absurd to me. I'm not going to participate in casual day.
You have fun though.
Yes we have too Mike. See it's casual day. It's fun. Come on, come on.
Fine, don't have business casual day you jerks.
Servo.
Huh.
Oh well be right back.
Am I done?
Yeah you can knock off for the day.
Okay.
Well can I dress like a turn of the century carnival barker?
It's very simple. If the spats are shiny and buttoned and the straw motor is well blocked, neat and free of hair fixatives, then yes you can dress like a turn of the century carnival barker.
Ah, the apes?
Ask them what they're wearing.
Huh? No, no I'm not going to do that.
The capacitor's going to kill you.
Hey don't worry about it Sporty. Discharge the capacitor already okay?
Oh, how do you do Brifes? Be with you in a second.
Well some neighbors dropped by and they brought their, what do you call this thing again?
The holy and everlasting balm.
Right and we're helping them fix their detonator, what I'm a hootie so that they can, how do you put that again?
Reveal our true selves onto the balm.
That's it, yeah.
Alright, let's give that a try.
Detonator circuit is non-functional.
Detonator circuit is non-functional. Detonator's out. You know I'm going to have to pull this whole thing out of here. Let's shut it down.
I've got trouble shooting here.
Balm has power but will not detonate. Balm will detonate but people aren't dying. I hear it is. Balm has no power and will not detonate.
It's as heated as you flim jumper J8 and the motherboard.
Hey, thanks for the help. I tried that already okay?
What I gotta do, you want to keep it down I'm trying to fix your balm here.
Why don't you and your statues take five while we try to fix this thing.
Oh my goodness they're messing around with a thermonuclear device.
Yeah and they're supposed to be sending us to movie. Cheese.
No you fool, the earth is going to be destroyed and take us with it unless we get the nanites to fix our ship now.
Hello nanites.
Yo.
We need our ship fixed and we need it fixed now.
Well I'm the only one here today, you got a work order?
Well no but I told you about it a long time ago.
Yeah. What's the name on that?
Nelson, Mike Nelson.
-Felson? -No Nelson.
-Felson right? -No Nelson, Nelson.
-Relson? -No, it's Nelson. What? Nelson.
Well I'm going to go check it back for that work order.
Why don't you have a seat Mr. Nelson and get yourself a cup of coffee.
Okay, thanks. Hurry up please.
Wow.
Well it's no use. The locking nut's frozen.
We need something to grab onto the hook while we crank on it from below.
Why don't you just use a pair of locking pliers and a spanner?
No Mike, Mike, Mike. Shhh.
That's brilliant. Thank you Nelson for your help.
-Do you hear that peanuts? -Yeah, I think it'll work.
Okay, let me grab it.
Okay, ready? Two, three.
Detonation in 30 seconds.
Congratulations.
Good one Nelson.
A wonderful bomb, a glorious bomb.
A wonderful glorious bomb.
A wonderful bomb.
Okay, what's the poop, boo boo?
And let's make it fast. I'm late for cardio boxing.
Yeah!
Well we armed our neighbor's thermonuclear device, lawgiver.
And I helped.
Okay, fine. Great.
You start the movie, put it on auto-execute,
and I'll be right back.
15 seconds to detonation.
Well Nelson, your movie today is the deadly master.
And by the way, what is a thermonuclear device anyway?
Please hurry up with that work order.
Well, I found it. Must have fell behind a desk.
Okay, great. So how long to fix the ship?
Oh, not long. There, it's done.
You have control of your ship.
Come on, I couldn't.
Whoa, they're quick.
Why didn't you do that weeks ago?
Hey, I don't go to the job without a work order.
Alright, here we go guys.
Alright Mike. Warp speed.
Yep.
And...
And gate.
Oh, right.
I feel a disturbance, as though a million monkeys cried out at once,
and then were silenced.
Yes. It's unimaginably horrible.
Yes, the earth is destroyed.
Oh, no, worse.
We got movie! No!
The world is closed due to massive amounts of snow.
Hey, shh, listen. There's a kind of hush all over the world.
And next we'll see Buckminster Fuller's Dimaxian version.
The map you're about to see is true.
It's a rather useless mall map.
Socks appeal level two.
When in the universe, be sure to visit the beautiful United States.
Oh, we're going to Nova Scotia. Good.
Some herring would be nice.
No, no, no, we're going to the British Isles.
Great to taste some Guinness.
I guess it's Morocco for some beautiful rugs.
We're going to go to the Ivory Coast then, for its lovely ivory.
And I guess we're going to the South Sandwich Islands.
Yes, I've got some family there in the Santa...
Oh, forget it.
Oh, Dot, I've always wanted to go there.
Somebody dropped a joint on the map.
Don't soak your map in nitroglycerin.
It's a magma-flowered savings at Menards!
Please call the gas company before digging.
The Earth's pores are opening like mad.
Yeah, the other planets refer to the Earth as "all pizza face."
For every action...
There is a Jackson.
There is an equal and opposite reaction.
There, I said it, and I'd say it again if I had to.
In Paraguay, a woman shops. Connection?
We take you now to a cold water flat in Brooklyn,
where another volcano is erupting.
You know what? Screw you, Greenland!
Yeah.
You're looking live at sold-out Greenland!
Oh, so we're not going to Greenland, then, apparently.
Apparently, the director was a former cartographer.
Because of volcanic activity, a creature named Santa Claus
crawled out of the ice.
He really had no idea what this movie was about, did they?
Here in the frosting mines of Canada,
the slaves of Betty Crocker were ground the clock.
Hey, it's spring in Minnesota.
Yeah, we tease Minnesota.
The icebergs arranged themselves for their long winter nap.
[wind blowing]
Summon Quee Quay gets the great white one.
Just a little wax on my undercarriage, please.
Oh, well, finally.
Scarring vanilla ice, ice cube, VVSnow, IceD, HintSnow.
And our super white cat.
For white rights, use Universal Movies.
Leon, Leon?
He had the laziest, most unimaginative parents in the world.
Hey, let me out! I got a foreign for a breadcrumb or something!
You know, behind the credits, you can see the ant of Turin.
I distinctly heard him say "Jew, Brandon."
If it could take a while, folks.
Radio Fremantus.
Please.
Curina Radarchow.
Deepsea Moss.
Your flight's very good.
And Wilson Pickett.
Canada, our mortal enemy.
You're on your own.
The northern network of electronic eyes.
The Mid-Canada radar fence.
As brutally graphic as this is, we needed to make a point.
Even farther north, in the very shadow of the North Pole, this fence.
A distant early warning system known as the "Dulai."
More like the "Don't want."
Ready to transmit the first warning signal of a sneak attack across the polar region.
Unfortunately, the Soviets attacked from Mexico.
To build the "Dulai," an armada of ships was assembled
in the largest and most secretly planned operation since the Normandy invasion.
Grinding through treacherous polar ice fields in a desperate gamble against time and weather.
How does the bug fit in?
It will land a mountain of supplies, machines, tractors, and men upon the ice.
Yes, in the glorious days before environmental impacts, Davis.
Building a better, snowless Arctic.
First things first.
We all went.
Level landing strips for heavy cargo planes.
More strip malls.
Then shelters for the men, for the planes, and for operations.
And while some hands are busy laying long pipelines to transport fuel,
others build tanks to store it.
Canada calls to ask, "What are you guys doing up there?"
The work continues day and night around the clock, seven days a week.
The corn palace is built.
Long last the ships are gone.
The summer is gone.
But the job is finished.
And the job was what again?
After all this work, how could we ever really disarm, you know?
Red Eagle 1.
Sentinel of the Arctic.
Nerve center of the Dulai.
His operation.
Good night, everyone.
Ah, don't land on our snow fort.
Colonel Parkman arriving to Spatch Jeep.
The plane overdid it on the lipstick.
Yeah.
The plane drops its eggs on the runway to be fertilized by mail planes.
Actors are shipped in from the mainland.
Colonel Parkman, who's on that?
Glad to have you with us.
Welcome to Ventriloquist Island.
Across the roof of the continent, still farther north.
I can't stop.
Outpost of the Dulai.
Want a dance, Ted?
It's our song.
The applause meter does not like this song.
Hey, Mike. Hey, Mike. Get a look at this.
There's a radar screen here.
Hey, there's crappies, 20 feet below the polar ice cap.
I don't see anything.
Except that giant deadly mantis.
Hey, wait a minute.
This one.
There's a mosquito in the house.
It's almost on top of us.
It's a confetti storm.
So, uh, you think it's gonna snow today?
Johnson and who goes for a haircut?
Ha ha.
Climbing without oxygen, Maria ascended to 20,000 feet.
Should he be up there on his respirator?
Don't they dump their garbage over the side?
This is Cain, Pickett 7327, calling Red Eagle 1.
Come in, Red Eagle 1.
This is Norm MacDonald.
Pickett 7327 is Red Eagle 1.
I'll read you over.
Put the old man on the horn, will you, Pete?
Oh, did he go last speed?
Roger.
I've got a ton of canes, sir.
Oh, let me talk to that little bitch.
Colonel Parkland, Walter, what's up?
We're over weather four, sir.
The building's been damaged.
Looks like the roof's caved in.
If there's anyone inside, they could be hurt or worse.
I'm sorry, sir.
I think of the kind of force it takes to destroy a Quonset hut.
Hey, let's loot the place.
Why a bassoon, you'll never know.
This is just stuff.
It's not antiques.
You know, maybe the army shouldn't have recruited Keith Moon.
Two men don't just vanish.
These did.
Well, you just don't get irony, do you?
There's some pancakes on the stove, you want some?
Rock and roll, just as I suspected.
I don't get it.
Everything was under control when they checked in at 0800.
Nothing unusual has been reported since then.
No storms.
There wasn't a gale that wrecked this shack.
It was a Debbie.
The sides are caved out as though something crashed into the roof.
I wonder if something crashed into the roof.
There was a plane that hit it.
Ah, don't say plane.
I beat your pants. I'm not sure how.
Maybe there's a very ordinary explanation for what happened.
Maybe the men are on the way back to the base right now.
On foot?
Who are you saying it isn't, commies?
The footprints in the snow.
Do you see any?
That was below the belt, sir.
Hey, it's really nice out.
There's Mantis scat out here.
Uh-oh, giant cross-country skiers.
Take a look here.
Bob says I can't come out. It's too cold.
What do you got?
Rhythm.
I don't know.
Then why'd you call me out here?
They're saving their oily rags.
A plane?
Oh, a peanut.
No plane. They were made that short of a run.
Guess I knew that. I'm sorry.
Helicopter?
Oh, a helicopter couldn't make a furrow like that.
Well, this isn't snow. It's bon-ami.
Damn, I dropped the plane keys here somewhere.
There is an ordinary explanation to what happened, but I wouldn't take any bets.
There's one thing we can be sure of. It wasn't a giant deadly mantis.
Django Reinhardt was here.
That's a nice snow sculpture, Steve.
But what about the dead guys?
They paid $12 million for this radar, and the fight's over in three minutes.
So the only recent contact you had with the weather shack was one of the helicopter drop supplies there five days ago?
Yes, sir.
You checked weather one?
Weather four made contact with them at 0813. Everything was Jake.
Did you check to see if I was gig young?
I'm picking up something, Colonel, but it doesn't make sense.
I'm simply not Jake.
I never saw a blip like that before. It's there, then it's gone.
I think that's the definition of a blip.
Hey, there it is again. What do you make of it?
I'm not taking any chances. Sound the red alert.
Skillet scramble horn.
Under the bob crane, scrambled to the rescue.
I'm scrambling, but where am I going?
Let's just get up there and fly and make it look like we're doing something.
Vector 360, climb to Angel's 3, bogey 90 miles.
Can I have my runway jerk?
A double pleasure is waiting for you.
Go first, big ones.
Complicated orthodontia.
Oh, this is where they grow in harvest pitcher's mounds.
Men commence tapping the Rockies.
Terrence, you have the whole air. Could you move over?
I'm trying later to control. Something here. Give us a new vector.
Bogey has disappeared. Return to home plate.
Well, that accomplished a lot.
Thanks, and good night, everybody.
And the slower, fatter plane tries to catch up.
I'm so baked right now. Dude, you gotta hear this rush tape.
Let's pull over for some Mickey cakes and Doritos, man.
Yeah, I got a yellow jacket in my headphones.
Did you forget to throw away that burrito from two weeks ago?
We haven't even left the ground yet.
A big kid put a quarter in the airplane.
I can't sleep. Tell me a story.
A mantis calls in air support.
Codependent Air Force planes.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, what are you doing? What are you doing? Can I come along?
What's going on? What are we doing? Where are we going?
Hey, stop eating me. I'm still alive.
Checkup find, the Red Eagle One. Come in, Red Eagle One.
Oh, geez, not again.
Hello, Checkup Finds. Red Eagle One. Go ahead.
Red Eagle One, we're over the wreckage of the C-47.
I didn't hear that. I got a lunch date.
Yes, sir.
Alert to the tender pilot. Yes, sir.
I'm suddenly thirsty for antifreeze. I don't know why.
Well, some fancy ski weekends for this plane.
Sir, let's just surrender to the Russians.
Hi, we're here about the reliant you had for sale.
Colonel.
Yellow snow, sir. Can I eat it?
Looks just like the weather shack.
Frosty the snowman's partially melted body was found at the site, a victim of a pistol whipping.
Herbie the misfit elf is wanted for questioning.
I think I can get it going.
Okay, we've investigated. Let's get out of here. It's freezing.
Got to put an end to free-basing on our planes.
Hey, go-go boot material.
Great hat. That's his hair, Mike.
Very slow synapses.
Where are the bodies?
Easy.
So easy, why don't you do it?
In their last futile attempt to save themselves, they taped their plastic salad bowls to the roof of the plane.
Look out!
The thing that almost didn't hit you!
I think they must have significantly underbid the FAA to conduct this investigation.
Ooh, what in the world?
What is it?
I don't know.
It's Flodjo's fingernail.
Looks like it had been broken off and something.
That point's as sharp as a needle.
No, it isn't. Come on.
Gentlemen, this looks delicious.
I give up. You got me.
Why can't we come in?
Well, where do we go from here?
We'll have to let Konad worry about that.
Konad? Konad?
This is Konad.
And you are?
The Continental Air Defense Command in Colorado Springs.
The focal point of the supersonic shield that guards the North American continent.
And children's palace.
A shield that could mean the difference between life and death for millions of Americans.
Phone races!
These are hot phones.
Using them, it takes only 15 seconds to talk to Alaska.
Time a minute.
10 seconds to alert Newfoundland.
Not that you'd want to.
5 seconds to contact you.
Me?
3 seconds to reach the Pentagon Command Post.
But it's a party line, so it's always busy.
General Ford speaking.
Excuse me, sir. The world just blew up.
Yes.
Hmm.
The brunch is canceled.
Sure.
Good. I'll take a plane right out.
I got a callback for carousel.
The Arctic Command has delivered the package.
And so we gather to remember Mrs. Pearl Forester, who was now passed from this mortal coil.
Amen.
Oh, and the several billion apes who perished from the blast too, thanks to Mike.
I don't think you can blame me for every single thing you did.
Mike, shut some respect.
Huh?
What to say about a woman like Pearl?
Yeah, what to say?
What to say, folks.
Well, she lived a life that was, well, she managed to live a life that, well, she was a lie, technically.
Boy, true enough, huh?
Pearl, weren't you saying something the other day about her that she wasn't as awful as one might think?
Oh, no, no, no, no.
I was talking about that show Nash Bridges.
It's pretty good.
It's got this cute lady--
Well, you get our drift, Lord.
Now that Pearl has gone over to the other side, or rather has been hurled violently to the other side, really, because of Mike's bottomless stupidity.
Why do you blame my bottomless stupidity for everything?
It is not-- hey.
Hey!
Oh, oh, oh, my gosh!
What's that?
I'm gonna get number nine!
Your reports of my death were greatly exaggerated, you crapheads.
I escaped with minor damage to the dude.
Now eat Len.
Oh, she's got that space man souped up the hack-and-bath.
She's out maneuvering me at every turn.
All right, baby, out!
Oh, don't, don't, don't!
Get it, gyps.
Ha! Nelson, you big sissy, making that oversized purple shop back two-yard driving for ya.
Oh, yeah, sister!
Well, you're gonna be eating my space dust!
Dream on.
I'm switching to my nine-iron dead girl.
What the hell is this, an old throw rug?
Ah!
Who is it?
I have a gun.
I have lots of guns.
It's only eye-logger for your record-serving.
Boo-boo!
You dared stow away on my ship?
No, I didn't really.
I just, well, the force of the blast must have thrown me into the doors of your own ship.
Save your pathetic excuses, you giant hairball.
Make yourself useful.
You ever use one of these?
Of course, Lug, if our civilization is far advanced in the use of weaponry and-
Oh, I suck my tongue!
You have never handled a piece of big feather!
Oh, I have, Lug, if it's just been a long time and I don't-
Oh, I suck my other tongue!
Shut up! We're losing them!
Wow!
Oh, nice job, Gypsy. You shook 'em here like the Shirley Muldowney of Deep Space.
Thanks.
Listen, I'm gonna down ship now.
Hang on! I'm gonna try to pull behind this asteroid!
Kill the lights, Mike.
Where the hell did they go?
Nice job, Gypsy. I think you shook 'em.
Phew, I need a giant fresco.
Serval, what's that supposed to be?
I'm idling.
We'll be right back.
Oh, stop.
Okay?
Okay.
The Devil's Hideaway.
Ah, they turned it into a place like that.
Good afternoon, gentlemen.
Good afternoon.
I'm General Ford.
Oh, no, no, no, please, sit down.
Now stand up again.
Gentlemen.
I'm honey.
I realize that the Air Force hasn't given you much time in which to make your tests.
And that a definitive job may have been out of the question in the short time you've had.
Where am I?
But the Department of Defense hopes that during these two days of concentrated efforts,
you've come to some conclusion about this.
Filmed in bald spot vision.
Professor Gunther, I believe you're in charge.
Yeah, you're a general, huh? I was a general when I was 16.
All of us are agreed to accept one thing.
Angela Lansbury's hot.
This appendage comes from some living creature.
Maybe me.
But as to what creature it was once a part of, we are completely in the dark.
Our anatomist, Dr. Arnold Burton, has been unable to identify this object.
It's in the very end, little one.
Professor Harvey pierces certain from his exploration that the hook cannot belong to the neurological system.
Yeah, but she's fighting it.
It seems to know more about what it isn't than what it is.
That is correct, sir.
There. That'll be half a billion dollars.
Get back in, you little boat grandpa.
Gentlemen, let's be logical.
This came from an elf.
Now you tell me that this hook comes from something that's alive. All right?
Wins jello!
But it wasn't a part of the cargo, and it wasn't in the plane when it took off.
So it must have come aboard after the crash, right?
That sounds logical.
Can I go home?
Now what was it that came aboard?
It shouldn't be so difficult. You know the animal life of the Arctic.
We have asked ourselves that, General.
Isn't that good enough?
You're not suggesting that it comes from some creature at present unknown.
It's a possibility we suggest you investigate, sir.
How?
We recommend that you ask Dr. Nedric Jackson of the Museum of Natural History here in Washington to look into this.
He's their chief paleontologist and the country's leading authority on the oligocene carnivory.
You lost me, Professor.
I thought I would.
He deals with life of past geological periods as shown by the fossil remains of plants and animals.
You're fascinating.
He has been able to reconstruct prehistoric creatures with no more to start with than a handful of bones.
Like me.
And he has a really nice house.
Lucille!
Oh, it's the random bones display.
I'm going to show everybody my binky portraitures.
Please take a number.
Hi, Mark.
Are you paleontology-ing?
What have you got there?
You cat.
My kids and my junior science group made it.
Even I had an extra vertebra, though it doesn't have enough already.
Here.
You want to count them?
Listen, if I'm ever to get next month's issue of the magazine out, we'd better start working.
I'll call my operatives.
I've done a feature.
Miss Mesozoic.
Life parades to the ages.
Sharing the progression of prehistoric creatures from the jellyfish to the dinosaur to primitive man.
It's a very simple three-step evolution.
Sounds all right.
And I'm going to include the pictures we took on your last fiocrit.
Blackmail!
That's even better.
Oh, excuse me.
That would be a phone and that would mean I have a call.
Jackson talking.
The Pentagon.
Sure, I'll wait.
Quick.
What do you know?
Maybe they want to call me back on the service.
This is Dr. Jackson.
General Ford.
General Tennessee Ernie Ford.
Yes?
Well, try lancing it.
I see General.
Of course, sir. I'll be right over.
General wants another foot massage.
Everything all right?
Of course.
He just demoted me to the gift shop.
Well, 'tis an everyday the Pentagon calls you.
It is so!
Very nosy.
Okay, be mysterious.
I'll just hang up your coat and hate you.
Well, if I tell you, you'll keep it a secret?
Hope to die.
They found an old bone up at the North Pole.
This is Bert Larr.
The Pentagon wants to know to whom it belongs.
Oh, and we've been invaded by Spain and mermaids are real.
Bye.
I hate that smug bastard.
Well, gentlemen, it appears to be a giant devil's food snack well.
Can't tell us a dang thing, can you, sonny?
Well, it doesn't look like bone.
More like gristle or cartilage.
It's your thumb, you dork.
The structure is large as this would have to serve a very specialized purpose
in order to be cartilaginous.
Have you any idea what it comes from?
No, not the faintest.
If it were bone, we could start from that.
It says "Made in Taiwan" here.
It does tell me, however, is that it can't be from an animal.
Because every known species of animal has a bony skeleton.
As a matter of fact, the reptile structure is bony.
I'm bony.
Even birds have bony skeletons.
Looks like we're getting nowhere fast.
On the contrary, we're making considerable progress.
At least we know what it can't be, which is bound to lead us to what it is.
Hello?
Or is there anything that doesn't have a bony skeleton?
Lots of things. Worms, snails, insects, shellfish.
Some invertebrates wear their skeletons on the outside.
Well, it's an outer shell called an exoskeleton,
which is hard and rigid enough to protect the internal organs.
I'm lonely.
Insects have thin, flexible places between their heads and bodies,
which allows them freedom of movement.
Who are you, man, and where's my soup?
Then they have folds where the muscles are attached.
Who's going to drive me home?
I can't see a thing.
That's where the process of elimination seems to lead us.
Please don't say elimination.
Of course, if it is an insect, it certainly doesn't tell us what kind it is.
Marie died, you know.
I've learned that partly from what we know, but mostly from what we deduce.
Doc, you're beginning to sound like Sherlock Holmes.
Sort of.
Professor Gunther, the fluid from the end of the hook.
You had it analyzed?
Well, we did what we could in the time we had.
Of course, you didn't know exactly what you were looking for.
Precisely.
I'm not too much of an anemologist, but I do seem to remember
that with very few exceptions, the blood of insects contains no red corpuscles.
Now that we suspect this hook may have come from an insect,
would you test the fluid for me and let me know what you get?
No.
Glad to. Thanks.
Well, General, that's about it.
Professor Gunther will make his tests and...
Probably screw it up.
We'll see what we can dream up.
Do you think we'll get somewhere?
Nah.
We'll do our best.
Charles de Gaulle Museum Guard.
Rob, I don't need to salute the paleontologist.
Get back here, you jerk. I saluted you.
I somehow don't believe Paul Drake was ever this deep in thought.
Bones just don't excite me anymore.
He's wearing David Byrne's suit.
Oh, damn. Another 10,000 holes in blackburn Lancashire.
Jeez.
New petitions against tax!
My God.
Look, Pensive. Stare straight ahead.
That's what they wanted to see you about.
You caused another polar tragedy, didn't you?
Don't you play games with me, Ned Jackson?
Not even our strip risk?
I'm sorry.
There's an old saying that you can't keep anything from the press.
And even if I'm only running a museum mag,
I haven't lost my nose for news.
That is what it's about.
Maybe.
I know it is.
Maybe not.
Why, it's as plain as the nose on your face.
The budget Rosalind Russell.
The Pentagon has never consulted you before.
The papers say they have a mystery on their hands.
One-in-one still makes two,
so it follows that they must need information in your field.
Oh, Ned.
You don't know what it would mean
if I could run a story about something that took place in this century.
Well, I...
I mean, I...
I didn't say it was restricted.
You see?
All right, it's...
Restricted.
It's like the paper says.
There have been crashes and disappearances.
But the real story is what they found at the last crash.
It...
Well, it's about five feet long.
It's...
It's mottled green in color.
A large leprechaun?
Probably broken off the body someplace.
Maybe mine. I don't know.
What are you talking about?
It's part of something alive.
Something that must be incredibly, unbelievably huge.
Well, it's almost big like.
I think it's from an insect.
An insect?
Here.
Ah, here. A happy, non-belated birthday.
Doesn't look very fearsome, reduced in size like that, does it?
The ant inside this amber is at least 90 million years old.
And so it's turned into a beetle.
Where? Where?
Now, we've been able to learn from pieces of amber like this
that certain ancient insect forms have continued without variation until today.
That others have changed to meet changing conditions
and certain species have vanished completely.
I just can't believe that an insect as large as you suggest ever existed.
Look behind you on the wall, Professor.
Ah, made you look.
What? Where?
That prehistoric dragonfly measures two feet from wingtip to wingtip.
And like the modern dragonfly, it too is a flesh eater.
All right, it's big, but it's only two feet.
Is that the best you can do?
I never suggested I was looking for a dragonfly.
So shut your fat god.
So what are you looking for?
To be honest with you, I'm not exactly sure.
What are you doing tonight, sweet cheeks?
You're a pathologist, Professor Gunther.
The field of pathology is limited.
It's pathetic.
But the paleontologist's field isn't narrow to what we understand.
On the contrary, we stretch our understanding to try and take in the universe.
All right.
Suppose, just for the sake of argument,
that we admit such an insect once existed.
How could it be alive today?
Exactly.
Even the recently discovered prehistoric Siberian mammals were dead.
The natives ate the flesh, used the skin for clothing,
made tools from the ivory tusks.
But the mammals were dead.
Are you sure they were dead?
Why?
Everyone knows they were.
Everyone says they were.
But everyone lies.
Suppose the Siberians hadn't been in such a hurry to slice them up for steak.
Suppose they were still alive when found in the ice.
Jerk.
Don't you learn a young friend always going like this?
All right, Professor.
You know as well as I do that a brother or wife is frozen quickly enough.
It is theoretically possible to stop the living cold of a present from chasing their human-experienced temper patterns,
which always happens when death occurs.
Beating.
Is it unreasonable and un-cathed yourself?
Whether the mammoths mightn't have remained alive all those years.
And it was the Siberians who killed them before they had a chance to thaw out and breathe again.
You can't Siberians rack everything.
You believe this?
Well, I don't disbelieve it.
I'll go along with it until someone comes up with a better theory.
Leave me alone.
Five men have vanished.
My heart.
The die is one thing.
Oh, yeah.
They disappear without a trace, suggest complete destruction.
A flesh-eating creature.
But there are scores of insects that live on other insects.
Where do you start?
By thinking of the hook as though it were infinitely smaller.
As though it were part of an insect no larger than those we know today.
Like, oh, the grass-upper, the beetle or the cricket.
Then ask yourself, what flesh-eating insect of normal size has such a hook?
They're making a lot of assumptions.
Chicken.
Every paleontologist does.
Dumb beetle.
You start with a jawbone, a couple of teeth.
You figure whether they come from a flesh or a grass-eater, and you go from there.
A normal insect that is a flesh-eater.
I've narrowed the field to one.
Should we narrow it further?
Mrs. Beatrice Targison of Maple Plain has spurs like that.
Diets consist mostly of small insects such as leaf-hoppers, grass-hoppers, caterpillars, and others.
Goof-goof.
A substantial part of the diet may also include small frogs and lizards.
The female is larger than the male and invariably destroys her mate when he's fulfilled his function in life.
Oh, sorry, this is about Ukrainians.
Now the hook they found on the plain may very well be a spur from one of its forelegs.
If this is it, as large as a monstrous creature we're looking for,
I doubt whether anything that ever lived could be as deadly.
It's strong beyond anything its size suggests.
It walks, leaps, and flies.
And snow-bards.
Its appetite is insatiable.
You mean this cute little bug?
Yeah, that cute little bug.
I see, I see.
In all the kingdom of the living, there is no more deadly or voracious creature than the praying man.
Hi, folks. Don't worry, I'll be in the picture from here on in.
Oh, big parallel bars there.
The blubber shipments in.
Yay.
Stop laughing with your wife and get out here.
It's the mighty Quinn.
Is there a sail on boll haircuts?
Come on up.
First down.
In you at Baywatch.
Hey, Mike, I can row a boat, can you?
No, I don't know what that means.
Everybody had a kayak across the Bering Strait.
Straight in and Chevy for a kayak, a-k-a-k-a-k-a-k.
Everybody's going to the store for chocolatey cocoa marsh.
That's one to the Gulf of Mexico.
Buy's lunch.
It's kind of bad timing there.
Just about to toss grandma out out of the tundra.
Riddling ranchers, riddling ranchers.
They're a thriving tobacco industry.
Dude, there's great waves out there, man.
Now I lay me down to sleep.
Good luck.
Bless us, O Lord, of these thy gifts.
Ha-ha-ha, get it.
You're my gift.
The Teflon mantis was acquitted in downtown Manhattan today.
Anything new on the disasters, General?
Nothing else, gentlemen.
Say, you're Dr. Jackson in the Museum of Natural History, aren't you?
That's right.
What have you been called in for?
Dr. Jackson is an old friend of mine.
That's not answering his question, General.
You're a fairly entologist.
Isn't this out of your line?
Have you any theories, Dr. Jackson?
Gentlemen, we just got married, okay?
If you were in my position, and what you had was a theory,
not facts, just a theory,
I'm sure you'd withhold it to avoid any speculation
that might prove disastrous.
I'm sure you realize this,
and that you'll cooperate with us to avoid panic or hysteria.
Or we'll have to declare martial law and shut down the papers again.
I know I can count on all of you.
I sure wish Hildy Johnson was still working.
Well, good luck to you, Ned.
Thanks. I'll do my best.
There goes the least limited paleontologist I've ever known.
Bound copies of Armored Master Magazine,
couple of tilde-roan bars.
- Joe Gray in drag. - All right.
Almost ready?
May I close this?
I'm told the Air Force doesn't like to be kept waiting.
Come on, come here. Make yourself at home.
- Whoo! - Thanks for breaking my nose, you creep.
- Nice of you to see me off. - I think so.
She's like a manly E-vardon, don't they?
Hide the bomb, hide the bomb.
You know, the Arctic's about the only place where I haven't worked in.
You have my makeup case.
- Are those mine, too? - No, doctor, they're mine.
- A woman with luggage? - Sure.
You couldn't go along without your photographer, could you?
- My what? - Well, I phoned General Ford's office
and requested permission for you to take your photographer along.
I guess he forgot to tell you.
Boy, this is really going to be a story.
You almost anything for a story, would you?
Almost.
Would you put clams up your nose?
Oh, come on.
Oh, he's gonna be a lot of fun on this vacation.
Wait up, Mom.
You know, she didn't want to have so many little planes,
but her husband was a DC-10, so he just couldn't keep his wings off her.
Look at that. It's a huge dead zebra up there.
Well, this is one of those plant-curling communities.
The teenage suicide capital of the world.
I think I just set a big bomb off.
Colonel, uh, Dr. Jackson is here from Washington.
He's got a... I mean, there's a...
- What's he got? - He's with the woman.
- With breasts and everything. - A female woman.
I thought they'd stop making them.
- Show them it. - Corporal Donnie Mosk.
Those gosh darn heteros. What do you get at it?
Come in, Miss girly, womanly, female, feminine, dame thing.
- Oh, where's the woman? - Oh, who?
I'm Ned Jackson, Colonel. I'm sure that Washington...
Luke Warmness at first sight.
Excuse me. This is Miss Marjorie Blaine, Colonel Joe Parkman.
General Ford sent me up. I'm magazine editor for the Museum of Natural History.
- How do you do? - How do you do?
I asked you first.
That'll be all, man.
I think this guy is familiar with dishonorable discharge.
You're gonna see strange things behind that glass, ma'am.
It looks like you don't have too many women up here, Colonel.
Well, we have a little joke up here.
Woman. Woman.
- Woman. - Show us your lady things.
[music playing]
No, no, no.
- Come on, come on. - Get better, I am.
- I am. - I am.
I'm okay. I'm okay.
- Better let me drive, my friend. - No. No, that's okay. I'm all right.
Hey, Mike, let's fire up the radio.
I'm a fantastic driver, and I should take the next 100 light years.
No, and again, no, Tom.
[music playing]
- Wow. - Wow.
That stinks out a lot, huh?
[music playing]
Stuff seems to be pretty popular.
You're occasions the quaint cloud and the bell of Orion.
Remember FDIC.
Your crank has turned to Frank. Here's zero.
[music playing]
Yeah!
What is this?
Are we in the southern portion of the galaxy now?
- Oh, jeez. - Girl, honey.
[music playing]
- Wow. - Sick dog.
- This is dumb. - This is--
Dad, you have put in a tape, why don't you?
- Yeah, I can come and help us out. - That's not good.
Hold on now. Let me spin around. We'll find something.
This is Nebula Public Radio.
- Oh, fine. - I'll find one.
At Nebula for over 200 years.
Hello, my friends.
This morning we pay tribute to the music of Skinny Wilson.
What? What?
[music playing]
Public Radio.
Oh, my God.
I like this song.
[music playing]
You'll love this. It's called popular music.
Don't ask, don't tell, but have a darn good time.
Vogue, all that you can, vogue.
[music playing]
- Daddy. - Oh, man.
He's Donnie Mosting out of control now.
Gentlemen, this is Ms. Marjorie Blaine.
I thought you wouldn't mind too much if she had a look around your recreation room.
Oh, she's like a butterfly, flying across the lily pond.
Oh, I'm yuck.
It's making Google eyes at your mom.
Yes, Corporal?
Bob Crane, what's up?
With your permission, sir.
Would it be all right if...
Would it be all right if I asked Ms. Blaine to dance, sir?
Corporal, that decision is entirely up to Ms. Blaine.
Yes, sir.
No hit, Mommy.
Well, Ms. Blaine, would you care to...
Love me?
What I mean is, well, I'm not...
At all attractive.
Corporal, I'd love to.
It's smooth as silk, huh? I still get it.
Ice station Fargo.
Well, he has the hardest time buying shirts.
With the things.
I will destroy Christmas this year.
I will.
A little town of death for him.
Well, remember the tension and breathtaking action of that map?
Wow.
Oh, man, these time cards are confusing.
Eight hours on one.
It's got curb feelers.
It's cold, my joints are frozen.
So the best minds my generation destroyed by madness.
Benedictus Quivini, the nomine domini.
Keep getting three. What the hell are you...
Oh, not the Motel 6.
Just gonna sneak in and borrow the snowblower.
Giant Mattis, come on in.
Hi.
Hi, Ned. Thought you were going to join us.
I haven't been busy. You two run along. Have fun.
What are you up to?
I'm trying to figure out how big this thing is.
I'm gonna need at least 12 rooms.
You know, people used to think that carnivorous plants were the bunk.
It's a peeping Mattis.
Actually, there are about 450 species up.
Some are almost six feet tall.
People think I'm fat, but I'm really just big exoskeleton.
I'm convinced that we're dealing with a Mattis
and whose geological world the smallest insects were as large as man.
And it's failing to find those insects for its food.
What'd you say?
Well, it's doing the best it can.
If there is such a thing, why hasn't anybody seen it?
Well, those who have are dead.
But there was no room at the inn for the poor Mattis on that wintry night.
Well, who can be sure?
It may have been locked in a prison of ice millions of years ago.
What could have released it after all that time?
Any sort of unusual vibration?
You know how mountain climbers are afraid of thunder?
Well, it's because the sound vibration might start an avalanche.
Is Dave there?
Look, shut up.
I'll just brush the snow out of the pond.
It's so clumsy.
Sorry.
My arm's stuck.
No, that's the can.
Oh, gone balsa wood houses.
I flip. I float. I fly.
Everyone check their anti-freeze. Quick!
Colonel Mami!
Schools out snow day. Yay!
Someone's who had deer in the parking lot.
Ah, sorry, just trying to get a heath bar.
Now, last night a raccoon and now this.
Oh, that slightly scraped my exoskeleton.
Ah, chemical peel. That feels good.
You know, I can only assume you're doing this on purpose.
Look, I just want my claw.
I'd like to point out that I mate and then I kill.
Mate.
Whoa, mantis belches. They're the worst.
Why, but he is stately.
It's totally boss and cool. I can't tear my eyes away.
Rodeo pounds.
He transmogrified.
I can't see a thing.
Lift us up where we belong, Roger.
Prepare to deploy giant facial tissue and smush the enemy over.
After a simple installation, you can enjoy five channels of porn.
I'm pretending I'm plating, but I'm really leering.
Tom and Jerry, ma'am.
Coffee, Colonel?
Head injury, Corporal.
It's fresh instant from concentrate.
The nutmeg was not fresh, sir. I'm sorry.
Nine hours, not a whisper.
I've been busy, Phil.
Which is all right with me.
It's like Ralph Wade after a bender.
I think I won this is Hunter Four.
Is Red Eagle One?
Is it for me?
Hello, Hunter Four, this is Red Eagle One. Go ahead.
We have nothing here. Request permission to return to base. Over.
No, I'm not here. No.
Request denied. Continue search procedure. Over and out.
There, Colonel Knob.
All we need to do is to keep the patrols out straight around the clock, though we're sure.
And remember, I want to report on anything from Mid-Canada or Pine Tree. Anything. You understand?
Oh, no, sir. I don't understand anything.
Finished planning my route to Sturgis.
Ten reckoning starring Humphrey Mantis.
Got my J.Crew shirt on all as well.
This is Colonel Fargman.
Oh, Colonel. Group Captain Hawkins, sir.
Yeah, Mucky Pop.
This is just a stab in the dark.
Could you, Chaps, ask us to report anything unusual and...
Yes.
As I said, it's a good thing.
Yeah, bugger around then.
A bit coggled.
Everything all bunged up.
Muffy flaps, sir.
Bit of a fizzy gig.
Limey bastard.
He's out of our jurisdiction.
He's not doing well. He's doing better than 200 miles an hour.
Why not, Joe? We're dealing with an insect.
The deer fly does 600.
An Arab can go Mach 5.
It's almost as fast as a jet.
The Mid-Canada line is 1500 miles south of here, right?
Right.
And where was that Weather Shack 4?
I don't know.
Right there, straight on the 80th Meridian.
And the C-47 crash was here.
That's why I do south of the Weather Shack.
Shut up, Iris.
Right there, between us and the C-47.
Wait a minute.
He's been going straight south.
And he'll keep going south until he reaches the tropics,
where he'll find the same kind of climate and jungle vegetation
from which he came originally.
Now, let's see. He'll probably pass over Labrador and Nova Scotia.
Then he'll hit the Gulf Stream.
And I'm sure the warm air above the Gulf Stream will attract him,
and he'll follow it all the way down to South America.
I've got Kona out on the hotline, Colonel.
They say it's important. Thanks.
Jesus Kona.
Colonel Parkman.
Are you sure?
Well, I mailed you the check.
I have no clue who that was.
I've regun it, too. It went through Newfoundland.
Well, it looks like we're on our way to Washington.
Come on, Mark. Grab your toothbrush.
It's in the enlisted quarters.
They have a natural instinct to fly below radar.
Mantis, wow, is crowded in Portland.
Wide-fear mantis mounting, too.
Oh, that Bob Dornan.
All over the United States this morning,
some 400,000 members of the Civilian Ground Observer Corps
are gathered to learn more about this fantastic creature.
The program is being presented by the
Cotton Metal Air Defense Command.
Our first speaker is Major General Mark Ford.
He's the very model of a modern Major General.
I want to say at the outset that, contrary to rumor
and certain newspaper headlines...
I'm not gay.
The so-called deadly mantis is no imaginary scare.
Some are.
It's a very real and present danger.
Starring Harrison Ford.
With me this morning is Colonel Parkman,
commanding officer of an advanced radar and receptor base
deep in the Arctic Circle.
Colonel Parkman.
Sorry, I dug a big hole for you.
Thank you, sir.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Lake me.
I saw this creature attack our base.
You're hurting me.
I visited the weather shack,
and I also inspected the wreckage of the aircraft
that this thing destroyed.
No, for God's sake.
I will have every reason to believe that the mantis is flying south
along the Gulf Stream.
And we believe that it will be one of you to vote...
The mantis!
...the women of the Sevegan Ground Observer Corps.
The Lamottas.
You bought it the next time it appeared.
I have with me today Dr. Nedrick Jackson,
curator of the Department of Paleontology
of the Museum of Natural History.
And his puppet.
Dr. Jackson has something important to show you.
Dr....
I think this is going out all over Upper Canada.
Gingivitis is a major problem in America.
This object is a spur broken off the foreleg of the mantis
when it destroyed the C-47.
Now for a word from Westinghouse.
The mantis is so small, it's difficult to measure.
This spur is making nearly five feet long.
Which will give you some ideas to the creature's size.
You can get this with your pledge of $50.
Now you ground observers are well trained
in the identification of aircraft.
Here is a boxing non-puppet.
The scale is the deadly mantis.
And here is the C-47, which it destroyed.
Separated at birth, you decide.
One other thing.
I made all of this up, you dopes.
You spotters should listen for a loud droning sound,
much like that of a squadron of heavy bombers flying in formation.
This will be me droning on.
A Coast Guard and the Navy have been alerted
and are standing by on the eastern seaboard.
The mantis is sighted, the procedure will be the same
as though an enemy aircraft had been spotted.
Scream like hell and die.
Take no chances.
Report any unusual flying object.
Now this for Medcel.
Meanwhile at the Imperial Palace in Beijing.
Well, 50's beach wearer is much more conservative.
Charles Whitman lends a hand.
Look harder, damn you.
Mantis land here.
And radar is there.
Ah, Pismo Beach and all the clams I can eat.
USS Walter Payton.
So why are there a whole bunch of dentists wandering around on the flight deck?
They called her and Radio Shack collaborated.
Quick, poopy suits on.
Get you move.
Right, let's invade the Falklands again.
I can't get the knot untied.
Hey, Oming.
Well, I suppose.
You know one of those things can hurt like Cadillac a mile?
Why would you want to?
That's a good question.
Jets.
Everyone's legs are sticking out.
I'm using my sunbeam facial mister.
Dan Fouts, fighter pilot.
His tip is off.
Fine, hell with you guys.
Wait, my thumb is stuck. I can't--
Sky King.
And Sky King.
What do you buy in a Biscuit?
I love my work.
Alright people, let's go kick some thorax.
Wait for me, Bob.
Yeah, me too.
Star equals 210, what the--
Whoa, we made some.
Come on, I'm unique.
Very rare.
That is one wily bug, gentlemen.
Yep, nonstop, high speed, aggressive, non-action.
Let's see, if I quit smoking, I can save $4 a week.
Let's go out over here now.
Yeah, here's better.
It's great here.
And now, morning reflections.
Whoa, pull up. Oh, it dozed off there.
Um, hello, movie, whenever you're ready.
The final desperate hours of the Dole campaign.
Where'd you out range?
Consolidated dust down 13.
Granary fire in Minneapolis.
Oh, that's grand.
Here's some power lines down there, Richmond.
Richmond, Virginia?
No, Richmond, the United Arab Emirates, wake up!
[music playing]
He's got about 15 museum magazine writers buried out here.
Wow, this is hot.
We interrupt this program to bring you a newsflash.
A trailer that's reported north of Laurel, Maryland, on US Highway 1.
The engine and five cars were overturned in what appears to have been a freak accident.
We will bring you further details as they come in.
It's only a few miles from here.
We'll have a look.
Well, see that we do.
Why don't they look, Ned?
Well, we got a good spot, anyway.
It's a touch of evil, too. This time it's a bug.
Sorry, Colonel, I've got a train wreck.
Let's move it!
Take care.
It's a detour to your left, to Laurel.
Or just come under here.
Pretty bad. It could have been a lot worse.
Could have been a train load of maggots.
How did that happen?
Bobby couldn't see the warning in the fog.
Can't tell for sure the engineer is still unconscious.
Joe, do you think it might...
Delay our dinner reservations?
No.
Just a max.
Come on.
Thanks.
Geez, in or out with you two. Come on!
She left one just before she gets in the car.
Oh, now.
Pish.
I think the train wreck put the cap on the evening that I needed.
Woo-hoo! Is that your hand?
Uh, could we have edited this?
Mantis slowly pulls out and follows them.
Ah! Something we're supposed to be able to see!
Ah!
Corner of Stappen Norton.
Present Tongue!
What's he doing with his jaw? That's chilling.
Oh, my God.
Looks like Scott Hamilton here.
It's too dangerous to drive in fog like this.
Remember what happened to that train back there?
She's retracting her neck like a turtle.
Brigadier General Love.
Colonel Feelgood.
But I got a Mantis in my panties.
You see, there's an Amanda Beardsley Film Festival I liked.
So, did you like meeting my privates?
I mean the guys back at the base.
Who the buses with us, my demons?
Oh!
You never come back!
Oh, you've got your packets, lady.
Thank you, driver.
I don't go to--
I mean you welcome.
You know, it's good to get home safely with all the strange things going on around here.
Oh, there's nothing to worry about, ma'am.
You just be careful out in that fog.
Thank you.
They must have sprayed for a deadly Mantis here.
She has a temp job at Baskerville Castle.
She's the waitress at the International House of Usher.
She's home from the war, so sad no one there to meet her.
Oh, the Mantis is systematically wiping out the transportation system.
I'm in control.
Do you go to Venice, well, ah...
The Mantis has joined the Birmingham Bus Boycott.
Hopefully John Madden was on that bus.
That would be nice.
The very latest report.
An interurban bus was demolished at the intersection of Fortin Avenue and Arlington Road.
The cause of the accident, which occurred only five minutes ago, is still to be explained.
Since there was no other vehicle involved.
This accident, in addition to the train wreck, which was reported a very short time before,
makes a total of seven accidents in this area within the last 24 hours.
Let's get that total up, people.
From this just in, the Colonel's advances will rebuff once again.
Sweaty hands slapped away, breasts escaped on the heart.
Ma'am, I have to ask you this. You have a giant exoskeleton.
Where'd you stash your 30-foot claw, ma'am?
I don't have a flange. It's up here. What happened?
I haven't got any idea, Colonel. Something must have lifted the bus and smashed it.
The front end's okay, so we know it didn't went into anything.
You boys might just as well go back. They're on any bodies.
Jose, take care of this lady for me, will you please?
Worker over. Make it tough.
Can that puts me back in the mood, honey?
Attention. All military and civil defense personnel.
You cannot be turned down for this policy.
All police and fire department personnel.
The mantis has been sighted over Washington.
I repeat, the mantis has been sighted over Washington.
Let's go.
It's a token motorcyclist.
That's General Alert.
Hey, they all came out of the same tent.
The President deploys a box of men.
Calling mantis man. Calling mantis man.
DM-4.
Mr. Mantis goes to Washington. Death.
Where's the outrage?
No, bat, down.
Bus drivers in love.
Jays, can you put a warning light on this thing?
Oh, I do not want to see this.
At least the government should make him some underpants.
He's segmented for an easy feat.
Rock. 369 Rock. Rock.
Andrew, can we use your Air Force Base, please?
We know you wanted to see more airplane preparation scenes.
Yes.
I swear I'm going to rinse this out someday.
Ah, it's chilly. I better put down the top.
That's the same jet. That's the same jet, chief.
Please go up. Come on, please go up.
You're grinding them.
I love how they're using jets from about 12 different areas.
Highway to the cheap stock footage.
Archers, this is Beagle 17. Airborne with four chickens heading 035.
What?
Over.
It's Colonel Parkman, sir.
You'll hang up and listen.
Beagle 17, archer control. Continue your present heading.
Boogie at 12 o'clock, 100 miles. Maintain present airspeed. Altitude at 5,000. Over.
Boogie fever, over.
Boogie tracking 150.
Grand Hotel, hold please. Grand Hotel, thank you. Grand Hotel.
I've got Baltimore, General. Go ahead, Baltimore.
Second plot, 340, range 150. Unidentified object. Speed, 250.
That's me, right there.
Altitude, 2000. Dropping fast.
Dixie, 35 Bravo. Range 150. Speed, 250.
Altitude now, 2000. Dropping fast.
I'm still moving northeast. You think you'll be able to drive it out to sea?
I hope so.
Police, I'm being peeped.
Air defense warning red. Stand by to lock off. Baltimore, warning red.
Fit it off your warning red. I repeat, red.
Blue, sir.
Attention Mitchell, field. Warning red.
So it's orange now.
Test to all gun sites. Guns free. Fire at any object. Not identified as friendly.
[Motorcycle engine]
Head out on that highway looking for adventure.
Yeah, sir.
Oh hi Mike.
Do you know how to drive?
That's exactly what I was wondering. Yeah darling, gonna make it happen.
Watch out, cause there's a thing in a road right up there.
I mean if you just kiss the left you're gonna have a lot of water.
Oh, look what you made me do.
You didn't make it.
Can't you give me rocket number nine?
[Motorcycle engine]
It is a creature.
Oh, I'll go get it, you big babies.
One of God's children, Mike, and if it's dead, I'll never forgive myself for letting you make me kill it.
I know, I know.
Hey, hey, it's alive. It's alive.
Hey, look at him.
He likes you.
Yeah, isn't that darling. Get away now.
Can we keep him, Mike? Can we keep him, huh?
Well, I don't know. I think we better release him back.
He's eating me.
Oh, he's not, bro.
Oh, come on, he likes you.
Oh yeah, he likes me. He's eating me.
Hey, down boy, down. You drop me.
You know what, I think he is eating him.
Ah yes, that's right. There is digestion occurring.
Wow, surprisingly caustic stomach fluid.
Hang on there, Crow. I think I have an idea.
Clear the deck.
That was me, Mike. Thank you.
Okay, I've got another idea.
Hang on, friend, Crow.
A little cherry bomb.
Oh yeah, I took most of that, Mike.
Look, I've been eaten. I'm gone. Goodbye.
One more idea, Crow. Hang on.
Mustard.
Jelly style. Okay.
All mustard.
Lepicac.
Oh, most of me does seem to be digestible.
Oh, cute.
Here we go. Come on.
Bring it up, buddy.
Oh, wow.
There we go.
Ah, you wisp.
There, see? He didn't mean to eat you.
Ah, look at me. Why don't you just tuck me back in?
We'll be right back.
Okay, spit, boy. Spit.
Rock, three, six, nine, rock.
Dixie, three, five, Bravo. Three, four, two, range, 110.
I win.
Victor, two, five, Victor. Three, five, two, range, 110.
Is this really all I can be?
Wow, the Earth has really built up over the last 30 million years.
This is Bernard Shaw. I'm under the table now.
Why don't they just open Earth's door and let it out?
The nation might be overreacting.
I'm turning into a wolf. Over.
Victor, two, five, Victor. Contact lost.
Dixie, three, five, Bravo.
I wish I wasn't Dixie, three, five, Bravo.
You've dropped below the radar net.
Well, does that mean you've lost it?
I don't know. What do you think?
One of the ground observers will pick it up.
I love you, Alice V. Toklas.
Keep watching the skies, Eleanor.
It's going stuck.
Joni and Patsy, look out.
Ron, this is one-nine hotels.
We have big O.
Go straight.
Let us down.
Yeah, James.
There you go.
Initial track, Bravo, go.
Do you guys have to stand there?
Three, three, nine, at two, five.
I drew it, Doc.
Eagle one, seven, Archer control.
Vector one, nine, or zero.
Bogy at 12 o'clock, steady on course.
Twenty miles over.
I'll check on your order, sir.
That'll put it over Newark in a few minutes.
Great. We can solve two problems at once.
Should we take down that big ape
on the Empire State Building while we're here?
Scooch over, over.
We accelerated to Mach one, but the deer fly's still outpaced us.
Top bug.
Archer, this is Beagle one, seven.
When steady on vector, Bogy will be 12 o'clock.
The June Taylor fighter planes.
Identify markings properly.
Make sure it's not a civilian passenger, Manus.
Over.
Ah, man, what a beautiful night for flying.
Hey!
Curse you, Red Baron.
I've been loooong.
He's really dainty when he's flying.
He's wearing a bustle.
Flame out on Hinder one.
He's beaten us. Suggest we turn over reins of power.
Archer control. This is Beagle one, seven.
Our farf.
We've splashed Manus.
Give me pigeons to home plate.
We really need you to stop talking funny and kill that big bug.
Over.
Bamsai, I'm divided.
He's got a nice lazy boy.
Good one, Colonel. Over.
What color is that parachute?
I love New York and June. How about you?
How about you?
Ten years later, meanwhile, the city holds us down
Poverty's sheets.
Why are you guys doing this?
Hey, Bud, it's said on television that the flyer who shot him down
has gone in the tunnel after him.
Did you see it crawl into the tunnel?
Good night, Mrs. Calabas.
Maybe this guy volunteered to smear himself with peanut butter
and stand on the Chrysler building.
It ain't out here, Mac.
Anybody killed?
I only know when I read in the paper.
Hey, smart guy, I thought I told you to stay under that road.
I'm going home. Get back here.
Mr. Winchell, please.
Stop the music. Stop the music.
Hey, a Swiss Army panel truck.
Oh, they're sending in Elizabeth Dole.
Fuck.
I think they've got ice cream in there.
Ice cream in there.
I'm going to dream sickles.
Maybe have a pop.
These sheets were trying to use our drinking fountain, sir.
That's all the smoke we need. Shut it off.
Wait, you needed smoke?
How much longer do you think it'll take?
Well, we've got about a 90% saturation of smoke in the tunnel now.
I don't think we can do any better, General.
We'll be lucky if we can hold what we've got.
Those red tarp mollins will hold the smoke all right.
Just keep pumping.
Thank you, sir. You keep pumping, too.
Hey, come on. I've got tickets for the metal lads.
Bishop Sheen, Mr. LaGuardia, Mr. Dewey.
How are we going to tow the mantis?
He's deadly, but he's parked in the yellow zone.
Mom made me wear my rain suit.
Everything's under control on the Jersey side, sir.
What about the smoke? It's back-dance solid.
Did you go inside?
Yes, sir, but we didn't get too close.
How far in do you estimate it to be?
I say about a quarter of a mile from this end.
That puts the mantis below the water line.
And your point?
I don't think we ought to wait much longer, sir.
Make it so.
No question in my mind that he's mortally wounded.
If we keep him in that tunnel, he'll die.
Is there anything between us and the mantis in this end?
17 cars, according to the automatic counter.
It breaks through those tunnel walls.
We'll have a flood on our hands.
We'll have to wait until a crybaby manta que.
What do you say, gentlemen?
Could be run.
Go ahead, Joe.
Let's go down to the Broadway show.
Good luck, Joe.
Joe's got back.
Gentlemen, let's do some beekeeping.
All right, man.
We've all been told what to do.
Ignored. It's all crap.
The purpose of that smoke in there is to give us cover.
Use it.
Now, which of you men are carrying the chemical mines?
None of us, I guess.
Stay up front with me.
And remember, those three R.G. mines are effective only in a limited area.
So watch for my signal before you throw them.
Hello?
All right, men. Check mass.
Your own mass.
Let's go.
I need to talk about our relationship right now.
She's wearing a good Republican cloth coat.
Meanwhile, in the men's bathroom at Giant Stadium...
Gentlemen, we face an enemy which is yucky.
I'm not wearing a thing under this, sir.
Thank God for the total little body condom, soldier.
I'm sure we'll have time to pop back and change after this.
I have theater tickets tonight.
Ironically, they still have to pay the toll.
The Gordon's fishermen go high-tech.
All you have to write to an entomologist.
If you're found guilty, you'll be pinned to a giant piece of cardboard.
Please send me in a stick and a couple pieces of grass.
I have nothing to perch on.
So much rage, so much anger.
I want the names of those Junebugs coming in from Utica, Mantis.
Kelsey, throw us the keys.
Well, I hope.
This guy's insurance only covers destruction by giant arachnids.
Um, sir, have we failed yet?
You look like a big percolator, sir.
That's enough, soldier.
Stop it.
Quiet!
It suddenly the lights come on in a car and the Mantis peels off.
Stop one of his many toes.
Um, sir, I'm not judging, but it seems like we should be able to find a giant Mantis.
This is a bug hunt, man. A bug hunt.
I can't see what it is.
Sir, when I was in the third grade, I bought a bug collection, never did the assignment.
I think I should be excused.
Oh, man, I got slammed.
Oh, sorry, just gotta clear my throat out.
I hired a 50-foot Alan Dershowitz to defend him.
What fruit look brigade?
And you overheat. What a rotten day, tell ya.
I think I see him.
Oh, that's a giant potato beetle.
I hope my operatives are all right.
What's the meat thermometer on my head say?
The cast of outbreak in the Untouchables.
Mantis is disguised as a highway worker, but his giant all-vipositor gives him away.
My Mantis isn't here. He just laughed. Thanks.
Hello, Colonel. I knew it would be you at the end.
Give me the weedies.
If we like you and I, Colonel, join me.
No, you care too much, don't you?
Ah, kiss my thorax.
Maybe he just wads a hog.
Sir, I just remembered he didn't tell us what your plan is or anything.
Let he go home.
Typical human. Bring a gun to a car fight.
Oh, sorry.
A Mantis. I'll spell M-A-N-T.
Quick, hose down another tarp.
Gollum is bigger than I thought.
I think he likes you, sir.
I got big eyes. That means I'm cute.
And with a mighty...
For some reason, this brings the Serbs into the war.
It smells like Vic's vapor rub.
Look at me. Don't see the someone who loved his mother before he ate her.
I'm just glad to know you guys are backing me up. I think we should... Hey!
Yeah, that's what I thought would happen.
Oh, those Eskimos are backing up on me.
See, the thing is, he was big and dumb even in his own time.
Funny guy, I guess.
The truckin'. Ha, ha, get it.
Why don't you ask me to leave and see what happens?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Oh, is that for me?
You see, the thing is, once he's dead, it's Mantis meets Amateur for months.
Colonel, if we frag you, don't take it personally.
Hi, deadly Mantis! Hi!
It was a good ride.
To all 50 million of my children I love them.
Move towards the Bodzapamentis.
I'm going down a long best trip.
I've tried to be a good Mantis. I've prayed.
Hold my hand.
I hear those gentle voices calling Big Green.
Tell the Eskimos that I deeply respect their culture, but also very delicious.
Now he expels Acrid burning fluids from every orifice.
They fast die really old.
Still, that was sadder than terms of endearment, you got it?
By coincidence, the coroner calls in sick.
There's got to be a morning after.
Hi.
We brought you a hot dish to see through your grief.
Visitation will be from two to four in the Lincoln Tunnel.
Anyone else filled with an overwhelming sense of regret?
Yeah, honey, I pretty much fragged him single-handed.
There's your cover for next month's magazine, Marge.
I don't know. We got good pictures of the volunteer appreciation luncheon.
This is as new as she ever gets.
Go on, take your pictures.
The Taliban militia, shocked by her conservatism.
Would you mind telling me what's so funny, Colonel?
Who, me? Nothing at all.
Can I help you with your camera?
No thanks.
Like, she's a real photographer. She's just a woman.
Take the picture, really, woman.
Woman.
Mr. Tiss, a question?
Exactly where did you crash into him, Joe?
Oh, is that me?
Just about center of the right-hand side.
If you'll follow me, I'll show you.
Can I get some ginger ale and saltine, I feel yucky.
What? How, how do I, I don't...
Yeah, baby, move a little closer, huh?
You ever been to the Copa?
I can get you in, baby.
We have received top clearance to play on him.
There, I think you can see right there.
He's a big boss.
Face the net.
Net, what are you co...
He's flipping us off!
MacGoth March!
My brownie camera.
Just wanted to cop a feel.
I thought you said you killed it.
Don't play him, Joel. That was an auto-reflex mechanism.
It's dead old.
Yeah, I got an auto-reflex mechanism right here.
Here, put me down.
I said put me down.
Don't you like it, woman?
What's the matter? Don't you like it up here?
I've got pictures to take.
Well, that can wait.
Intimidate the press.
This is no place for romance, Joe Parkman.
You'll never get my good stuff.
What about my pictures?
Oh, there'll be pictures, all right.
He felt the warmth of her body through the 13 layers of heavy cloth clothing.
I don't feel bad for losing my girlfriend.
Real funny.
Well, I couldn't make it here.
I couldn't make it anywhere, I guess.
And hit it!
Now, are we supposed to read this from right to left or left to right?
You know, I don't think any of these people are players to tell you the truth.
The heck was Mrs. Farley? Was that the Mantis?
Yeah, General Kingsley Pissypants Muttman played by Donald the Puss Randolph.
So are they assuming we all have terrible reading disorders?
What the heck is this?
And!
Keep watching the ground!
Please, let's forget it, we'll leave you.
I made a meat loaf!
Wow, would you look at that, I thought we were out of meat.
Oh no, we had meat.
Oh wow, try a little of that there.
Oh, no, that is delicious.
Unusual texture.
But with a nice blend of spices.
And I made gravy.
Oh, what do you know, man?
Aren't you going to have some, Crow?
Oh, I did already. You go ahead and eat.
Munch munch.
That's delicious.
I have something to ask you. How's that creature we hit earlier?
Oh, he's fine. He's juicy.
You know.
Juicy?
Did I say juicy?
I meant he's well marbled with a kind of Pequant aftertaste.
I mean, he's good.
Isn't he?
Malfoy!
We're lost in time and space, Malfoy.
Yeah, but the service is really good up here.
Look, it's a letter from Peanut.
Peanut!
Oh, look at this, Peanut.
He says, "Dear Mike and all, blast from end of world,
hurled me back in time to the year 2112."
Weather's been great. Living Wisconsin met a nice girl.
And he sent a picture.
He says her name is Ludmilla Nelson.
Relative of yours, Mike?
Oh, come on. I mean, what are the odds of that?
Why don't you put that on still, store-there, cat?
Yeah, put that up there.
I see your resemblance, Mike.
Congratulations, Mike.
Come on. Doesn't look anything like me.
Oh, Mike, your precious granddaughter or your lovely big-bone, great granddaughter.
Whatever. It's certainly a joyous day for any Nelson woman
when she meets the ape of her dreams.
Oh, Mrs. F is calling.
Mrs. F.
Nelson, you shook me once, but I'm still here.
Never forget that.
Foghead log-in?
Yeah, whatever.
Because, Nelson, you can never escape me.
Hey, sweet corn, let's stop her some sweet corn.
No, I don't want to stop her sweet corn.
Wherever you go, Nelson, I will be there.
More sweet corn and pumpkins and birds. Let's get a bird.
Look, are you bored? Do you want a drive?
Sure.
All right.
I got it. I got it.
Wait, I'm looking.
I got a idiot. I can wait.
Mrs. Nelson, I will hunt you down.
I will find you, Nelson.
It's no matter where you go, Nelson.
We'll be there with Mrs. F.
Oh, I'm so...
Bobo!
[MUSIC PLAYING]
Oh, she's like a butterfly.
[INAUDIBLE]